let MCQS = [{
             question: "Bauxite has the Composition ?",
    choice1: "Al₂O₃",
    choice2: "Fe2O3.2H2O",
    choice3: "Al2O3.nH2O",
    choice4: "none of these",
    answer: 2
},
            {
             question: "IUPAC Name of [Cr(NH3)3(H2O)3] Cl 3?",
    choice1: "Tetraamminecarboncobalt(3)chloride",
    choice2: "Diamminesilver(1)chloride",
    choice3: "Triamminetriaquachromium(3)chloride",
    choice4: "Pentaamminechloridocobalt(3)ion",
    answer: 2
},
            {
             question: "IUPAC name of the complex K3[Al(C2O4)3] is …………….",
    choice1: " potassiumtrioxalatoaluminium (3)",
    choice2: "potassiumtrioxalatoaluminate (2)",
    choice3: "potassiumtrisoxalatoaluminium (2)",
    choice4: "potassiumtrioxalatoaluminate (3)",
    answer: 3
},
            {
             question: "Which type of isomerism is exhibited by [Pt(NH3)2Cl2] ?",
    choice1: "Geometrical isomerism",
    choice2: "Linkage isomerism",
    choice3: "Optical isomerism",
    choice4: "Coordination  isomerism",
    answer: 0
},
            {
             question: "Formula of tris (ethane-1, 2-diamine) iron (II) phosphate …………?",
    choice1: "[Fe(CH3 – CH(NH2)2)3] (PO4)3",
    choice2: "[Fe(H2N – CH2 – CH2 – NH2)3](PO4)",
    choice3: "[Fe(H2N – CH3 – CH3 – NH3)3](PO4)2",
    choice4: "[Fe(H2N – CH2 – CH2 – NH2)3](PO4)2",
    answer: 3
},
            {
             question: "XeF6 on complete hydrolysis produces …………",
    choice1: "XeOF4",
    choice2: "XeO2F4",
    choice3: "XeO3",
    choice4: "XeO2",
    answer: 3
},
            {
               question: "Among the following, which is the strongest oxidizing agent?",
    choice1: "Cl2",
    choice2: "F2",
    choice3: "Br2",
    choice4: "I2",
    answer: 1
},{
               question: "Among the following the correct order of acidity is …………?",
    choice1: "HClO2 < HCIO < HClO3 < HClO4",
    choice2: "HClO4 < HClO2 < HCIO < HClO3",
    choice3: "HCIO < HClO2 < HClO3 < HClO4",
    choice4: "HClO3 < HClO4 < HClO2 < HCIO",
    answer: 2
},
            {
               question: "When copper is heated with cone HNO3 it produces …………",
    choice1: "CU(NO3)2 , NO and NO2",
    choice2: "Cu(NO3)2 and N2O",
    choice3: "CU(NO3)2 and NO2",
    choice4: "Cu(NO3)2 and NO",
    answer: 2
},
            {
               question: "Crystal field stabilization energy for high spin d5 octahedral complex is…………….",
    choice1: "– 0.6∆0",
    choice2: "0",
    choice3: "2 (P – ∆0)",
    choice4: "2 (P + ∆0)",
    
    answer: 1
},
            {
               question: "Solid CO2 is an example of ………..?",
    choice1: "Covalent solid",
    choice2: "Metallic solid",
    choice3: "Molecular solid ",
    choice4: "Ionic solid",
    answer: 2
            
},
             {
               question: "The number of carbon atoms per unit cell of diamond is ………..?",
    choice1: "4",
    choice2: "1",
    choice3: "8",
    choice4: "6",
    answer: 2
            
},
            {
             question: "The Crystal with a metal deficiency defect is ………..?",
    choice1: "NaCI",
    choice2: "FeO ",
    choice3: "ZnO",
    choice4: "KCI",
    answer: 1
            
},
       
          {
             question: " Which one of the following reaction represents calcination? ",
    choice1: " 2Zn + O2 → 2ZnO ",
    choice2: " 2ZnS + 3O2 → 2ZnO + 2SO2 ",
    choice3: " MgCO3 → MgO + CO2",
    choice4: "Both (a) and (c) ",
    answer: 2
            
},
           {
             question: " Which of the metal is extracted by Hall-Herold process? ",
    choice1: " Ni",
    choice2: " Al ",
    choice3: " Cu",
    choice4: " Zn ",
    answer: 1
            
},
    
  









];